Register of the John Vaizey Papers, 1926-1985
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1960-1984
  - President, Queens' College, Cambridge, n.d. (Folder 45)
  - Purslow, Louise, 1976 (Folder 46)
  - Pyke, Susan, 1983 (Folder 47)
  - Pyres, Norman, 1976 (Folder 48)
  - Queen Elizabeth Military Hospital, Includes correspondence with others; materials relating to John Vaizey's hospitalization, 1981 (Folder 49)
  - Quirk, Randolph, 1984 (Folder 50)
  - Radcliffe-Rand?, John, 1976 (Folder 51)
  - Rafael, G.?, 1976 (Folder 52)
  - Rafroidi, Patrick, 1984 (Folder 53)
  - Raman, David, 1976 (Folder 54)
  - Ramsey, E. M., 1966 (Folder 55)
  - Ranger, James, 1981 (Folder 56)
  - Rauf, M. N., 1965 (Folder 57)
  - Read, Tom, 1976 (Folder 58)
  - Rear, John, n.d. (Folder 59)
  - Reeve, Robin, 1980 (Folder 60)
  - Richardson, G. B., n.d. (Folder 61)
  - Richardson, W. N. B., 1976-1980 (Folder 62)
  - Ridgway, Huldine, 1976 (Folder 63)
  - Riley, Tim, 1976 (Folder 64)
  - Ritcheson, Charles, 1976 (Folder 65)
  - Rittner, Luke, Includes Arts Council of Britain, "Arts: Facts and Figures," 1982, 1984. (Folder 66)
  - Robinson, Sir E. A. G., 1976 (Folder 67)
  - Roll, Sir Eric, 1976 (Folder 68)
  - Ronnen, Meir, 1977 (Folder 69)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, Includes correspondence with Rt. Hon. Lord Annan, Alan Bullock, A. H. Halsey, T. B. Smith, Ben Whitaker; Quentin Anderson, "Practical and Visionary Americans," n.d., offprint; memoranda; prospectus and other materials relating to John Vaizey's residency at the Rockefeller Foundation's Bellagio Study and Conference Center, Italy, 1972-1975. (Folder 70)
  - Roth, Gabriel, 1980-1981 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Rowberry, G., 1980 (Folder 2)
  - Rowntree, B. Philip, 1976 (Folder 3)
  - Royal Academy of Music, 1983 (Folder 4)
  - Royal Institute of International Affairs, Includes correspondence with Rt. Hon. Lord Boyle, notes and other materials relating to John Vaizey's application for the position of Director, 1977. (Folder 5)
  - Rubenstein, Hilary, 1976 (Folder 6)
  - Rudner, Martin, 1974 (Folder 7)
  - Rutter?, Colin, 1976 (Folder 8)
  - St. John-Stevas, Norman, Includes program for conference on the arts, 1978-1980. (Folder 9)
  - Samuel, Ian, 1980 (Folder 10)
  - Sapper, Laurie, 1976 (Folder 11)
  - Sayce, Olive, 1977 (Folder 12)
  - Sayce, Richard, 1967-1968 (Folder 13)
  - Sayce, Sylvia, 1980 (Folder 14)
  - Sayer, T. D., 1976 (Folder 15)
  - Schifferli, Maguida, 1980 (Folder 16)
  - Scott, P. F., 1983-1984 (Folder 17)
  - Scruton, Roger, 1984 (Folder 18)
  - Selby-Smith, C., n.d. (Folder 19)
  - Sergeant, Patrick, 1976 (Folder 20)
  - Shackleton, E., 1976 (Folder 21)
  - Shamash, David, 1966 (Folder 22)
  - Shaw, Martin, 1978 (Folder 23)
  - Shaw, Roy, 1976 (Folder 24)
  - Shersby, Michael, 1984 (Folder 25)
  - Silver, Pearl, 1978 (Folder 26)
  - Singer, Francis, n.d. (Folder 27)
  - Singh, K. Natwar, 1984 (Folder 28)
  - Singh, Khushwant, 1976 (Folder 29)
  - Skelmersdale, Lord, 1984 (Folder 30)
  - Slater, T. F., n.d. (Folder 31)
  - Smethurst, Richard, 1969-1973 (Folder 32)
  - Smith, Nico J., Includes photocopy of open letter written by Smith, n.d., 1983. (Folder 33)
  - Smith, Randall, 1976 (Folder 34)
  - Smulian, Rahna, 1978 (Folder 35)
  - Snow, Lord, 1976 (Folder 36)
  - Social Affairs Unit, 1983 (Folder 37)
  - Society of Remedial Gymnastics, Includes correspondence and notes relating to grant eligibility for Remedial Gymnastics and Recreational Course, 1982-1983. (Folder 38)
  - Sorgen, Dick, 1962 (Folder 39)
  - Sowrey, F. B., n.d. (Folder 40)
  - Spencer, Arthur, 1983 (Folder 41)
  - Spens, Lord, Includes correspondence with Rt. Hon. Tom King, 1984. (Folder 42)
  - Spicer, 1984 (Folder 43)
  - Squires, Jack E., 1976 (Folder 44)
  - Stacey, Nicholas A. H., 1976 (Folder 45)
  - Stadler, Nick and Frances, 1976 (Folder 46)
  - Stansky, Lyman and Ruth. Includes correspondence of Lady Vaizey, their daughter
    - General. Enclosures, primarily clippings pertaining to Lord and Lady Vaizey (Folder 47)
    - Undated (Folder 48)
    - 1962-1979 (Folder 49-57)
  - Stansky, Peter and Billy, 1972-1981 (Folder 58)
  - Steel, David, 1976 (Folder 59)
  - Stelianopoulos, Jose Manuel, 1978 (Folder 60)
  - Stephenson, Donald, 1976 (Folder 61)
  - Stewart, Michael, 1976 (Folder 62)
  - Stiby, Robert, 1983 (Folder 63)
  - Stitt, Kenn, 1968 (Folder 64)
  - Stone, Peter B., 1976 (Folder 65)
  - Storr, Anthony, 1980 (Folder 66)
  - Stowe, Sir Kenneth, 1984 (Folder 67)
  - Straubenzee, W. R. van, 1976 (Folder 68)
  - Streeten, P. P., 1976 (Folder 69)
  - Stroll, Avrum, 1981 (Folder 70)
  - Strong, Julia and Roy, 1976 (Folder 71)
  - Swaffield, Sir James, 1978 (Folder 72)
  - Symn-Crampton, Raymond, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Symon, Jean, 1976 (Folder 2)
  - Symonds, Matthew, 1984 (Folder 3)
  - Szczepanski, Jan, 1979 (Folder 4)
  - Taylor, Marian, 1976 (Folder 5)
  - Taylor, Richard, 1976 (Folder 6)
  - Teeling-Smith, George, 1983 (Folder 7)
  - Thatcher, Margaret, 1970-1981 (Folder 8)
  - Thomas, Hugh, 1981 (Folder 9)
  - Thompson, Peter J., 1980 (Folder 10)
  - Thorneycroft, Lord, Includes correspondence with Conservative and Unionist Central Office, 1979-1981. (Folder 11)
  - Thorpe, Rt. Hon. Jeremy, 1968 (Folder 12)
  - Thynne, Michael, Includes correspondence with others, notes and other materials relating to review of Thynne's sentence for rape and buggery, 1979. (Folder 13)
  - Tomlinson, J. R. G., 1976 (Folder 14)
  - Tong, Alfred, 1982 (Folder 15)
  - Townsend, Lena, 1976 (Folder 16)
  - Trend, 1984 (Folder 17)
  - Trevor-Roper, Hugh, 1979 (Folder 18)
  - Trier, P. E., 1976 (Folder 19)
  - Truro, The Bishop of, n.d. (Folder 20)
  - Tweedsmuir, Lord and Lady, 1977-1978 (Folder 21)
  - University College, London, Includes notes and other materials relating to John Vaizey's application for the position of Provost, 1978. (Folder 22)
  - University of Canterbury, 1979-1980 (Folder 23)
  - University of Lancaster, 1977-1979 (Folder 24)
  - University of Oxford, Includes notes and other materials relating to John Vaizey's application for the position of Director of the Institute of Agricultural Economics, 1978-1979. (Folder 25)
  - University of California, San Diego, Includes correspondence with U. S. Treasury Department, Internal Revenue Service, 1966-1981. (Folder 26)
  - Urry, Sydney A., 1976-1982 (Folder 27)
  - Vaizey, Theo, 1976 (Folder 28)
  - Venning, Philip, 1984 (Folder 29)
  - Villiers, Sir Charles, 1984 (Folder 30)
  - Wainwright, David, 1976 (Folder 31)
  - Wallace, William, 1983 (Folder 32)
  - Walton, H. C. M., 1980 (Folder 33)
  - Watermen and Lightermen, The Company of, Includes materials relating to John Vaizey's membership, 1982. (Folder 34)
  - Watson, Steven, 1976 (Folder 35)
  - Watt, Donald, n.d. (Folder 36)
  - Watts, William, 1976 (Folder 37)
  - Weidenfeld, Sir George, Includes prospectus for Ben Gurion University of the Negev Foundation, 1975. (Folder 38)
  - Weiler, Hans, 1976 (Folder 39)
  - Weiserbs, D., 1983 (Folder 40)
  - Wertheimer, S., 1978 (Folder 41)
  - Wetherley-Mein, G., 1984 (Folder 42)
  - Wheldon, H., 1976 (Folder 43)
  - Whishaw, Sir Charles, 1976 (Folder 44)
  - Whitaker, Ben, n.d. (Folder 45)
  - Whitney, Ray, 1984 (Folder 46)
  - Wilkins, N., 1983 (Folder 47)
  - Williams, Desmond, 1976 (Folder 48)
  - Williams, G. L., 1976 (Folder 49)
  - Williams, Owen, 1976 (Folder 50)
  - Williams, Shirley, 1965-1983 (Folder 51)
  - Wilson, Rt. Hon. Sir Harold, Includes a speech by Sir Harold Wilson, 1971 Sept. 8, and materials relating to John Vaizey's elevation to the peerage by Wilson, 1976, 1964-1983. (Folder 52)
  - Wolfers, David, 1976 (Folder 53)
  - Wolfson, G. M., 1984 (Folder 54)
  - Wood, Michael, 1976 (Folder 55)
  - Woodham-Smith, Cecil Blanche, Includes copy of address at Woodham-Smith's memorial service, April 29, 1977, 1964-1977. (Folder 56)
  - Woolton?, Barbara, 1976 (Folder 57)
  - Wraight, Anthony, 1976-1981 (Folder 58)
  - Wright, Sir Oliver, 1980 (Folder 59)
  - Yasa, Memduh, 1984 (Folder 60)
  - Young, Baroness, Includes notes on a trip by John Vaizey to Cyprus, 1984. (Folder 61)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1951-1980
  - General
    - General
      - Clippings. Primarily references to John Vaizey, 1963-1981 (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
      - Contracts, 1958-1983 (Folder 5)
      - Correspondence. Publishers and literary agents, 1971-1984 (Folder 6-8)
      - Lists, n.d. (Folder 9)
    - Broadcasts, British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC). Includes interviews with Joan Robinson and Gunnar Myrdal, conducted by John Vaizey, 1963-1984 (Folder 10)
    - Drama, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Letters to editors, 1961-1984 (Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, notes and fragments (Folder 3-6)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, notes and fragments (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Reviews. Typescripts and clippings (Folder 2)
    - Speeches. Typescripts and clippings, 1962-1977 (Folder 3)
  - General, Clippings, holographs and typescripts (Folder 4)
  - "Aspects Economiques de l'Education," Printed copy, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - "Economic and Social Development in Educational Planning," Typescript (Folder 6)
  - "Economic Change--Cultural Change: An Essay," Printed copy, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - "L'Education dans le Monde Moderne," Printed proof sheet (?) (Folder 8)
  - "Higher Education in the " n.d. Typescript, 1970's (Folder 9)
  - "A Note on Comparative Statistics," Printed copy, n.d. (Folder 10)
  - The Trade Unionist and Full Employment, Pamphlet (Folder 11)
  - General, Printed copies, 1951-1953. (Folder 12)
  - "The 'Burden' of Education," Fabian Journal, Printed copy, 1953 July. (Folder 13)
  - The Cost of Social Services, Pamphlet, 1954. (Folder 14)
  - General, Printed copies, 1954-1957. (Folder 15)
  - Success Story, Pamphlet, 1957. (Folder 16)
  - "The Theory of Social Expenditure," Administration, Proofs and printed copy, 1957 May. (Folder 17)
  - "Teachers' Superannuation in England and Wales," British Journal of Educational Studies, 1957 Nov. (Folder 18)
  - General, Printed copies, 1958. (Folder 19)
  - "Education in a Rich Society," Typescript, ca. 1958. (Folder 20)
  - The Costs of Education, Printed copies of reviews, 1958. (Folder 21)
  - "Block Grants and Control of Education," Political Quarterly, 1958 April-June (Folder 22)
  - General, Printed copies, 1959. (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - "The Finance of Higher Education in the United Kingdom," Year Book of Education, Proofs, 1959. (Folder 2)
  - Scenes from Institutional Life, Drafts, printed copies, and reviews, 1959. (Folder 3)
  - Untitled, Typescript relating to American education, 1959 May. (Folder 4)
  - General, Printed copies, 1960. (Folder 5)
  - General, Printed copies, 1961. (Folder 6)
  - Guinness's Brewery in the Irish Economy, 1961
    - General. Expense information, background materials, comments, fragments and drafts, clippings, and illustrations, 1958 (Folder 7)
    - Correspondence
      - 1955-1957 (Folder 8)
      - 1958 Jan.-Feb. (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - 1958 March-April (Folder 2)
      - 1958 May-June (Folder 3)
      - 1958 July-Nov. (Folder 4)
    - Reviews (Folder 5)
    - Early drafts (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
    - Final draft (Folder 4)
  - "The Reform of Higher Education," Printed copy, 1961 Feb. (Folder 5)
  - "Comparative Notes on Economic Growth and Social Change in Education," Comparative Education Review, Printed copy, 1961 June. (Folder 6)
  - "Education as Investment in Comparative Perspective," Comparative Education Review, Printed copy, 1961 Oct. (Folder 7)
  - General, Printed copies, 1962. (Folder 8)
  - "Teaching in a Modern Economy," Printed copy, 1962. (Folder 9)
  - Education for Tomorrow, Printed copies of review and text revision for later edition, 1962. (Folder 10)
  - The Economics of Education, Typescript and printed copies of reviews, printed copy in Spanish translation, 1962. (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - General, Printed copies and typescripts, 1963. (Folder 2)
  - "El Lugar de la Educacion en la Estrategia del Desarollo Economico," Revista de Economia Latinoamericana, Printed copy, 1963. (Folder 3)
  - Education in a Class Society, Printed copy, 1963. (Folder 4)
  - The Control of Education, Typescript and printed copies of reviews, printed copy in Italian translation, 1963. (Folder 5)
  - "Memorandum of Evidence," Typescript for the Central Advisory Committee on Education, 1963 Dec. (Folder 6)
  - General, Printed and typescript copies, 1964. (Folder 7)
  - " Scrutiny and Education," Essays in Criticism, Printed copy, 1964 Jan. (Folder 8)
  - "The Labour Market and the Manpower Forecaster--Some Problems," International Labour Review, 1964 April (Folder 9)
  - General, Printed and typescript copies, 1965. (Folder 10)
  - "The Civil Service in a Capitalist State," The World of Philosophy, Printed copy, 1965 March. (Folder 11)
  - "Demographic Considerations in Integrated Planning of Educational Levels," Typescript, 1965 Sept. (Folder 12)
  - General, Typescripts and printed copies, 1966. (Folder 13)
  - Education for Tomorrow, 1966. Reviews, correspondence and miscellany, 1965-1966 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - "Planning to Afford Education," Forum, Printed copy, 1966 Aug. (Folder 2)
  - Barometer Man, 1967
    - General. Correspondence and reviews, 1966-1969 (Folder 3)
    - Drafts and comments. Typescripts and holographs (Folder 4-6)
    - Proofs (Folder 7)
  - "Weightlessness; or Reflections on the Afflictions of Our Time," Acton Papers, Typescript, ca. 1966-1967. (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - General, Typescript and printed copies, 1967. (Folder 2)
  - "Higher Education in the Stationary State," Printed copy, 1967. (Folder 3)
  - The Costing of Educational Plans, Printed copy, 1967. (Folder 4)
  - Education in the Modern World, 1967
    - General. Correspondence, reviews and miscellany, 1969-1980 (Folder 5)
    - Proofs (Folder 6)
    - Printed copy (Folder 7)
  - "Education and the Irish Economy," Sociology of Education Abstracts, Printed copy, 1967. (Folder 8)
  - General, Printed copies and typescripts, 1968. (Folder 9)
  - Resources for Education, Printed copies of reviews, 1968. (Folder 10)
  - "A New Constitution," Printed copy, 1968. (Folder 11)
  - "Demography and Economics of Teacher Education," Colston Papers, Printed copy, 1968. (Folder 12)
  - The Sleepless Lunch, 1968
    - General. Reviews, correspondence, and miscellany, 1967-1968 (Folder 13)
    - Draft (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Proofs (Folder 2)
  - "Future Pattern of Resouces for Education," RIBAJ Journal, Printed copy, 1968 Aug. (Folder 3)
  - "Education and Economic Development," Sociology of Education Abstracts, Printed copy, 1968 Dec. (Folder 4)
  - "Disenchanted Left: Thoughts on the Crisis," Encounter, Printed copy, ca. 1968-1969. (Folder 5)
  - General, Typescripts and printed copies, 1969. (Folder 6)
  - "Money Matters and Teachers Matter,", 1969 March (Folder 7)
  - "Keynes," The Irish Banking Review, Typescripts and printed copy of a speech relating to John Maynard Keynes, 1969 April-June. (Folder 8)
  - General, Printed copies, 1970. (Folder 9)
  - Textbook, Correspondence, draft fragments, notes and miscellany relating to a proposed textbook on applied economics, ca. 1970. (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - The Type to Succeed, 1970
    - General. Correspondence and reviews, 1969-1971 (Folder 2)
    - Drafts (Folder 3-6)
    - Draft (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Final draft (Folder 2)
  - "Antecedentes Socioeconomicos y Educacion," Revista de Ciencias de la Educacion, Printed copy, 1970 Aug. (Folder 3)
  - "The Nature of Freedom in Contemporary Society," Typescript and printed copy of speech, 1970 Sept. (Folder 4)
  - Industry and the Intellectuals, Printed copy and reviews, 1970 Nov. (Folder 5)
  - General, 1971 (Folder 6)
  - The Costs of New Educational Technologies, Printed copies, 1971. (Folder 7)
  - Social Democracy, 1971
    - General. Correspondence and reviews, 1969-1973 (Folder 8)
    - Draft (Folder 9)
  - Capitalism, 1971
    - General. Correspondence and reviews, 1971-1972 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Illustrations. Photocopies of photographs used in the book (?) (Folder 2)
    - Draft (Folder 3)
    - Proofs (Folder 4)
  - "The Costs of Wastage," University Quarterly (?), Printed copy, 1971 Spring. (Folder 5)
  - "Manpower Forecasting and Economic Theory," Typescript, 1971 Oct. (Folder 6)
  - General, Printed copies, 1972. (Folder 7)
  - "Education and Government Policy," Proceedings of the Royal Institution of Great Britain, Printed copy, 1972. (Folder 8)
  - The Political Economy of Education, Reviews, 1972. (Folder 9)
  - Education, Reviews, 1972. (Folder 10)
  - Some Thoughts on Higher Education Expenditure, Printed copy, 1972 July. (Folder 11)
  - "Student Revolt," Symposium, Printed copy, 1972-1973. (Folder 12)
  - General, Printed copies, 1973. (Folder 13)
  - "Emergence of a British Economist," International Social Science Journal, Printed copies in English and French, 1973. (Folder 14)
  - The Economics of Education, Reviews, 1973. (Folder 15)
  - The Economics of Research and Technology, Reviews, 1973. (Folder 16)
  - "Words," Typescripts and proofs, 1973. (Folder 17)
  - General, Printed copies and holograph manuscript, 1974. (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - The History of British Steel, 1974
    - General. Primarily reviews, 1974-1977 (Folder 2)
    - Notes and sources (Folder 3)
    - Draft (Folder 4)
    - Galley proofs (Folder 5)
  - "What Does Government Finance do to a University," Printed copy, 1974 Aug. (Folder 6)
  - General, Printed copies, 1975. (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Whatever Happened to Equality?, 1975
    - General. Reviews and fragments (Folder 2)
    - Reference materials (Folder 3)
    - Draft (Folder 4-5)
  - Speeches, Relates to John Vaizey's political activities and tenure in the House of Lords, ca. 1976-1984.
    - Clippings (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts. Holographs and typescripts (Folder 2)
    - Printed session transcripts (Folder 3)
  - Going on the Stage, Report to the Calouste Gulbenkian Foundation. Printed copy and clippings, 1975. (Folder 4)
  - Economic Sovereignty and Regional Policy: A Symposium on Regional Problems in Britain and Ireland, Proofs, 1975. (Folder 5)
  - "Problemas de la Economia de la Educacion," Revista de Educacio n, Printed copy, 1975 Jan.-April. (Folder 6)
  - "In Defense of General Economics," Australian Economic Papers, Printed copy, 1975 June. (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - "The Options at the End of the L6 a Week Period," Reward: Employment Market Survey, Printed copy, 1975 Oct. (Folder 2)
  - General, Printed copies, 1976. (Folder 3)
  - Education: The State of the Debate in America, Britain, and Canada, Reviews, 1976. (Folder 4)
  - "Point de Vue Economique sur les Media," Media, Printed copy, 1976 March. (Folder 5)
  - General, Printed copies, 1977. (Folder 6)
  - Economics for Everyone, Reviews, 1977. (Folder 7)
  - "La Financiacion de la Ensenanza Universitaria en el Reino Unido," Revista de Educacion, 1977 Jan.-April (Folder 8)
  - "Education, Skill Supply, and Reform in the Portuguese Economy," Conferencia Internacional sobre Economia Portuguesa, Printed copy, 1977. (Folder 9)
  - General, Printed copies, 1978. (Folder 10)
  - Training Musicians, Report to the Calouste Gulbenkian Foundation. Printed copy and clippings, 1978. (Folder 11)
  - "Science, Technology, and Man: Population and Education," Printed copy, ca. 1978-1979. (Folder 12)
  - General, Printed copies, 1979. (Folder 13)
  - "The School in Question: An Economist's Viewpoint," Oxford Review of Education, Printed copy, 1979. (Folder 14)
  - "Wartraits," 1979-1981. Series of articles written for Harper's & Queen magazine under the pseudonym James Zeitlinger. Correspondence, drafts and printed copies (Folder 15)
  - General, Printed copies, 1980. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Capitalism and Socialism, Reviews, 1980. (Folder 2)
  - "Economic Growth as an Endogenous Process--Human Resources and Motivation," 1980. Proof, printed copy and correspondence, 1980-1981 (Folder 3)
  - "What Books I Please," Typescripts of a BBC broadcast on Thomas De Quincey, 1980 (Folder 4)
  - "About Britain," Typescripts and correspondence, 1980 April-May (Folder 5)
  - General, Printed copies, 1981. (Folder 6)
  - "The Future of Socialism: A Retrospect," The Cambridge Review, Printed copy, 1981 April. (Folder 7)
  - "What is Wrong with the Economy and How to Put it Right," Drafts for a proposed book, ca. 1981-1983 (Folder 8)
  - General, Printed copies, 1982-1983. (Folder 9)
  - "Universities in Britain Today,", 1982 (Folder 10)
  - "Politics of Optimism," Typescripts of a BBC broadcast and correspondence, 1982 Oct. (Folder 11)
  - General Electric Company history. Relates to a proposed book (?)
    - General. Correspondence and notes, 1982-1983 (Folder 12)
    - Reference material and notes
    - Drafts (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
  - Report, 1983. Correspondence, printed material, holograph and typescript drafts, final copy, and miscellany relating to South Africa, 1983-1984 (Folder 3)
  - In Breach of Promise, 1983
    - Reviews (Folder 4)
    - Drafts (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - The Squandered Peace, 1983
    - General. Primarily reviews (Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1983 (Folder 3)
    - Draft (Folder 4)
    - Drafts (Box 35, Folder 1-6)
    - Drafts (Box 36, Folder 1-2)
  - General, Typescript and printed copies, 1984. (Folder 3)
  - "Welfare in " 1984. Typescript and letter, 1990 (Folder 4)
  - National Health, 1984
    - General. Correspondence, reviews and miscellany, 1983-1984 (Folder 5)
    - Draft (Folder 6)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1926-1984
  - General. Clippings, 1966-1980 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Academic Council for Peace and Freedom. Correspondence, lists, press releases and miscellany, 1983-1984 (Folder 2)
  - Advisory Commission on Professional Manpower. Lists and summary statement (Folder 3)
  - Art. Printed reviews, 1984 (Folder 4)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies. Correspondence and seminar materials, 1974-1977 (Folder 5)
  - Brunel University. Clippings, 1975-1976 (Folder 6)
  - Cumberland Lodge. Correspondence, report, printed materials, and miscellany, 1979-1984 (Folder 7)
  - Dalton, Hugh. Letters, including correspondence and a register relating to papers of Lord Dalton deposited in The British Library of Political and Economic Science by John Vaizey; newspapers collected by Lady Dalton relating to a railroad strike, and a royal wedding, 1926-1981 (Folder 8)
  - Economics. Clippings, 1965-1983 (Folder 9)
  - Education. Printed articles and clippings, 1964-1979 (Folder 10-11)
  - Foreign affairs. Clippings, 1976-1980 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Politics. Clippings, 1966-1984 (Folder 2)
  - Northern Ireland. Clippings, 1971-1980 (Folder 3)
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development. Clipping and description, 1975 (Folder 4)
  - Philippines. Letter from Imelda Marcos and miscellany relating to a trip (for a meeting?), 1976-1978 (Folder 5)
  - Public Schools Commission. Clippings, 1968-1980 (Folder 6)
  - Town and country planning. Report, correspondence, printed material, legislation, House of Lords session transcripts, and miscellany, 1982-1984 (Folder 7)
  - Travel. Clippings, 1971-1977 (Folder 8)
  - UNESCO. Correspondence, report, printed material, and a pamphlet, 1983-1984 (Folder 9)
- PHONOTAPES.
  - Two phonotape recordings of a BBC interview with Joan Robinson, conducted by John Vaizey, 1976 Jan. (Oversize Tape cabinet)
- PHOTOGRAPHS.
  - 20 portrait prints of Hugh Dalton, undated (Envelope A)
  - 30 prints of Hugh Dalton; 1 print of A. Guiness, circa 1882 (reproduction); 1 print of a painting of John Foster, Baron O'Neil, circa 18th century, undated (Envelope B)